Aaron Noel De Leon

Manila, Philippines aaronnoeldeleon@gmail.com | +63916 837 5550 http://nelonoel.github.io

SUMMARY

I'm an experienced web developer focusing on front-end development and UI design. I've worked with local and global startups; designing and implementing web apps from the ground up, and pushing regular updates for thousands of users.

EXPERIENCE

Vyllage | Front-end Developer & UI Designer | Feb 2015 - Jan 2016

Working remotely with a globally distributed team, I've managed to communicate my ideas and turn the company's product into a completely new, thoughtful experience for the users.

- Tested and designed user experience and product flow.
- Designed prototypes and high-fidelity mockups using Sketch and Invision.
- Lead the front-end implementation using SASS and ReactJS.
- Used complementary technologies such as Webpack, Gulp, and Reflux.
- Wrote unit tests for components using Jasmine.

Voyager Innovations Inc. | Front-end Developer | Jun 2014 - Feb 2015

Developed responsive web apps used by up to a hundred thousand users.

- Smartnet 2.0 (*now Safezone*): Smart's very own social network, which also aggregates feed from users' social accounts.
- Voyager Developer Portal: Public APIs of Voyager products.
- Takatack: Philippines' online marketplace. (http://takatack.com)
- Smart Places: a mobile app for location-based reminders and actions.

UE Research & Development Unit | Team Leader | Jun 2011 - Apr 2014

- Developed software and facilitated system deployments for various university events. Systems include: Event Registration, University Student Council Election, Pageant Management, Battery Exam Tutorial Enrollment and the UE API.
- Designed and developed web and mobile applications for competitions outside the university. Applications include:
 - Ellen: Chatbot and Community Mobile App (Philippine Commission on Women)

- The Cooking Colonel: Advertainment Mobile Game (KFC Philippines)
- Pledgr: Charity Work Recommender (GlobeLabs)
- Ang Budget Mo: Crowd-Sourced National Budget Allocation (Department of Budget Management)
- phTweet: Filipino Twitter Analytics (TrendMicro)
- and Casa San Miguel: Charity Organization Website (Philippine Web Designers Organization).
- Facilitated member and non-member trainings about web technologies (PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS), and design (Adobe Photoshop, Fundamental UI/UX Concepts).

ACHIEVEMENTS

Here Hackathon

Here Maps Philippines 1st Runner Up, 2014

Readysaster Hack Philippine Open Data Initiative 1st Runner Up, 2014

Caritakathon Philippine Web Designers Organization Champion, 2014

Magna Carta for Women App Dev Contest Philippine Commission on Women 2nd Runner Up, 2014 3rd National Debugging Challenge Polytechnic University of the Philippines *Champion*, 2012

KFC Youth Innovation Challenge De La Salle University 3rd Place & So Good Design Special Award, 2012

Web & IT Summit: Code Challenge & Web App Development Competition AMA Computer University, Quezon City *Champion*, 2012

EDUCATION

University of the East, April 2014

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Summa Cum Laude (GPA: 1.17)